EN

Open menu

\[us\] English <-> \[de\] German \[us\] English ---> \[de\] German \[de\] German ---> \[us\] English \[us\] English <-> \[fr\] French \[us\] English <-> \[es\] Spanish \[us\] English <-> \[br\] Portuguese \[us\] English <-> \[it\] Italian \[us\] English <-> \[ru\] Russian \[us\] English <-> \[jp\] Japanese \[us\] English <-> \[cn\] Chinese \[us\] English <-> \[pl\] Polish \[us\] English <-> \[nl\] Dutch \[us\] English <-> \[se\] Swedish \[us\] English <-> \[dk\] Danish \[us\] English <-> \[fi\] Finnish \[us\] English <-> \[gr\] Greek \[us\] English <-> \[cz\] Czech \[us\] English <-> \[ro\] Romanian \[us\] English <-> \[hu\] Hungarian \[us\] English <-> \[sk\] Slovak \[us\] English <-> \[bg\] Bulgarian \[us\] English <-> \[si\] Slovene \[us\] English <-> \[lt\] Lithuanian \[us\] English <-> \[lv\] Latvian \[us\] English <-> \[ee\] Estonian \[us\] English <-> \[mt\] Maltese More languages

[ä](javascript:addLetter('%C3%A4');)[ß](javascript:addLetter('%C3%9F');)[ü](javascript:addLetter('%C3%BC');)[ö](javascript:addLetter('%C3%B6');)

EN

* * *

DE

Privacy Policy Linguee
======================

The Linguee service is provided by DeepL SE ("DeepL"). The protection of your privacy and your personal data is very important to us. For this reason, DeepL collects and uses your personal data exclusively within the framework of the statutory provisions, in particular the General Data Protection Regulation ("GDPR") and the German Federal Data Protection Act ("BDSG"). With this privacy policy we inform you about the type, scope and purpose of the collection and use of your personal data. You can access this information at any time on our [website](http://www.linguee.com/page/privacy.php).

1\. Controller/Contact/Data Protection Officer
----------------------------------------------

Responsible for the processing of your personal data within the meaning of the GDPR, German Federal Data Protection Act (BDSG), other data protection laws applicable in the member states of the European Union and other data protection regulations is:

**DeepL SE**  
Maarweg 165  
50825 Cologne  
Germany  

The company's data protection officer is Dr. Christian Lenz, he can be contacted at the address dhpg IT-Services GmbH, Bunsenstr. 10a, 51647 Gummersbach, by e-mail at datenschutz(at)dhpg.de or by phone at +49 2261 8195 0.

2\. Scope of Data Protection
----------------------------

Data protection concerns personal data as defined in the GDPR, i.e. all information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person. An identifiable natural person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, online identifier or one or more special features.

3\. Automatic Data Collection about Website Access
--------------------------------------------------

When you access our website, your device automatically transmits certain data for technical reasons. The following data is stored separately from all other data which you may transmit to us:

* Date and time of access
* Browser type and version
* Operating system
* URL of the previously visited website
* Requested domain
* Search term when using a web browser
* Shortened/anonymized IP address
* Full IP address (for a maximum of 14 days)

The processing is carried out in accordance with Art. 6 (1) (f) GDPR on the basis of our legitimate interest in improving the stability and functionality of our website. The data are stored for purely technical reasons and are not associated with a specific person. The data on website accesses are used for error analysis, to ensure the security of the systems and to log accesses. The storage of the full IP address for a maximum period of 14 days is in our legitimate interest according to Art. 6 (1) (f) GDPR to achieve the listed purposes.

4\. Feedback and Questions
--------------------------

For feedback and questions of any kind please contact . If you have questions about privacy and data protection at DeepL, you can contact us at . The data processing for the purpose of contacting us is carried out in accordance with Art. 6 (1) (a) GDPR on the basis of your voluntarily given consent. For the processing of your inquiries to these e-mail addresses, we use the ticket system of the provider Zendesk Inc. ("Zendesk"), 989 Market Street 300, San Francisco, CA 94102, USA. In the course of this, your data may be transferred to the United States of America. We have entered into an agreement with Zendesk for the processing of orders and Zendesk may therefore only process the data in accordance with our instructions and not for its own purposes. For more information on how Zendesk handles personal data, please click [here](https://www.zendesk.com/company/privacy-and-data-protection/).

5\. Cookies
-----------

We use "cookies" to provide you with a variety of functionalities and to improve your user experience. Cookies are small text files which your browser files and stores on your computer. If you do not wish to receive cookies, you can disable the storage of cookies on your computer by changing the settings of your browser accordingly. Please note that if you disable cookies in general, the functionality and scope of the website may be affected.

In particular, we use the following categories of cookies:

* Necessary: These cookies are necessary for our website to function properly and for you to use its most important functions and to navigate smoothly. This includes security features, functionalities that allow easy access and settings such as the display language of the website and the translation language. We set these cookies because it is our legitimate interest to present our translation service as well as our company in general. The legal basis for the processing is Art. 6 (1) (f) GDPR.
* Performance: To continuously improve our website, we collect data for statistical and analytical purposes. We use these cookies to measure, for example, how often users return to our website and which functions they use. We only set these cookies with your explicit consent on the basis of Art. 6 (1) (a) GDPR.
* Comfort: We use these cookies in order to enhance the convenience of the website for you. For example, we remember which areas of the website you have already visited and to enable you to make the best use of our website. We only set these cookies with your explicit consent on the basis of Art. 6 (1) (a) GDPR.
* In order to provide advertisements on the website, we work together with selected cooperation partners (third party providers) who also set cookies. Within the scope of this, your data may also be transferred to the United States of America. These cookies are set on the basis of legitimate interests in accordance with Art. 6 (1) (f) GDPR or with your explicit consent on the basis of Art. 6 (1) (a) GDPR.

Here you can find an overview of the cookies set by DeepL:

| Category | ID  | Description | Technology | Expiry |
| --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
| Necessary | cookieLoginAuth | Used to guarantee the origin of a request to the translator and protect from malicious visitors. This ensures that the service is not compromised for the remaining visitors. | Cookie | 2 years |
| Necessary | ForeignLang | Used to remember selected language pairs in order to show appropriate sample translations/dictionary entries. | Cookie | 2 years |
| Necessary | dap.sid, dap.sid\_updated | Session ID and timestamp. Automatically deleted after 30 minutes of inactivity. | Session Storage | Session |
| Necessary | euconsent-v2, snconsent | Stores your preferences for cookie consent. | Cookie | 1 year |
| Notwendig | footer-overlay | Saves status for editor banner. | Cookie | 1 year |
| Comfort | preferredMp3Langs | Used to store preferred language dialect for playing dictionary entries. | Cookie | 1 year |
| Performance | uid | First-party user identifier. | Local storage | Unlimited |

You can manage your settings here [here](#), e.g. you can revoke your consent at any time. The Cookies are stored in your browser until they are deleted or, if it is a session cookie, until the session has expired.

6\. Linguee App
---------------

We offer a Linguee App for iPhone and iPad as well as for Android. The apps use the same interfaces for searching for translations as the web-based service.

If you use the app for a search, your device automatically transmits certain data for technical reasons. The following data is stored separately from all other data you may transmit to us:

* Date and time of access
* Version of the app
* Operating system
* Shortened/anonymized IP address
* Full IP address (for a maximum of 14 days)
* Diagnostic information in case of errors

The data are stored for purely technical reasons and are not linked to a specific person. The data on accesses are used for error analysis and to ensure the security of the systems. The full IP address is stored for a maximum of 14 days out of our legitimate interest in achieving the listed purposes.

We also use cookies in our apps. For further information, please refer to section 5. Due to technical reasons the use of cookies cannot be disabled in our apps. If you do not agree with the use of cookies in the app, please delete the app and use the web-based service alternatively, where you can manage your cookie settings according to your wishes.

7\. Data Security
-----------------

Your connections to our website are protected with state-of-the-art encryption techniques. The level of protection also depends on which encryption your internet browser supports. You can tell whether an individual page of our website is transmitted in encrypted form by the display of the closed key or lock symbol in the status bar of your browser. We also use suitable technical and organizational security measures to protect your data against accidental or deliberate manipulation, partial or complete loss, destruction or unauthorized access by third parties. Our security measures are continuously improved in line with technological developments.

8\. Your Rights
---------------

You have the following rights granted by the General Data Protection Regulation. If you wish to exercise any of the rights below, please contact us by e-mail at .

* Right to confirmation and right to information - we will gladly confirm whether we process personal data of you, what data it is and for what purpose it is processed.
* Right to correction - if the data stored with us is incorrect, we will of course be happy to correct it.
* Right to deletion - should you wish your personal data to be deleted, we will comply with your request as far as legally possible. If data must be stored for legal reasons, it will be blocked. The data are then no longer available for further use.
* Right to limitation of processing - if you wish to limit the use of your data, we will comply with your request as far as legally possible.
* Right of revocation - should you wish to revoke your consent, we will follow your request. However, your revocation does not affect the lawfulness of the previous processing of your personal data.
* Right to object - if your personal data are processed on the basis of legitimate interests pursuant to Art. 6 (1) (f) GDPR, you have the right to object to the processing of your personal data pursuant to Art. 21 GDPR for reasons arising from your specific situation or to object to direct marketing. In the latter case, you have a general right of objection, which you can exercise without giving reasons and without incurring additional costs.

You also have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority regarding the processing of your personal data, such as the data protection supervisory authority responsible for us: State Commissioner for Data Protection and Freedom of Information North Rhine-Westphalia, Kavalleriestrasse 2-4, 40213 Düsseldorf, e-mail: poststelle@ldi.nrw.de.

9\. Changes to the Privacy Policy
---------------------------------

We reserve the right to change this privacy policy. The current version of the privacy policy can be accessed on our [website](http://www.linguee.de/page/privacy.php) at any time.  

Last updated: September 2020

Most frequent German dictionary requests: [1-200](https://www.linguee.com/english-german/topgerman/1-200.html), [\-1000](https://www.linguee.com/english-german/topgerman/201-1000.html), [\-2000](https://www.linguee.com/english-german/topgerman/1001-2000.html), [\-10000](https://www.linguee.com/english-german/topgerman/2001-10000.html) , [\-30000](https://www.linguee.com/english-german/topgerman/10001-30000.html), [\-100000](https://www.linguee.com/english-german/topgerman/30001-100000.html), [\-200000](https://www.linguee.com/english-german/topgerman/100001-200000.html)  
Most frequent English dictionary requests: [1-200](https://www.linguee.com/english-german/topenglish/1-200.html), [\-1000](https://www.linguee.com/english-german/topenglish/201-1000.html), [\-2000](https://www.linguee.com/english-german/topenglish/1001-2000.html), [\-10000](https://www.linguee.com/english-german/topenglish/2001-10000.html) , [\-30000](https://www.linguee.com/english-german/topenglish/10001-30000.html), [\-100000](https://www.linguee.com/english-german/topenglish/30001-100000.html), [\-200000](https://www.linguee.com/english-german/topenglish/100001-200000.html)  

(© DeepL SE, 2024)
